forward. Just if we are thinking through the P&L on margins, the gross margin level
we have now, you know, sort of captures most of the interest or negative interest. And
then, you know, how much of that is going to impact? Should we sort of expect this to
be the level from which you can build based on when you get growth from, you know, younger
products in the portfolio while you, you know, get the profit growth through, you
know, SG&A management and, you know, R&D phasing, obviously, growth in second half.
So just in terms of gross margin trough point, should we be thinking about now or later?
Thanks for the question, Rajesh. So I think gross margin, we already said we had this
discussion beginning of the year, and I think it's the point on the gross margin where we
are now is a good point to take from modeling for the future. And what we already said is
end of last year, Q3, Q4 of last year, if you take an average of that, that should be
the gross margin point that we take.
But
worth saying is that gross margin would never be flat. It depends on the profit mix that
we have from a quarter on quarter perspective. And as we move the portfolio forward, there
are pushes and pulls that we have in our portfolio. We've got a great drug if comes
to life like remibrutinib, a small molecule. We don't have any royalties versus some of
our other portfolio where the gross margins would be more stretched.
But I think from a modeling perspective, I would take the year to date gross margin
as a good indicator of what to expect for year to go.
Thank you very much.
Thank you. As a reminder, if you wish to ask a question, please press star 1 and
1 on your telephone and wait for your name to be announced. Please limit yourself to
one question and return to the queue for any follow up. We will now go to the next question.
And the next question, Rajesh, is , that will be asked.
Three, two, one.
Go, please.
Thank you very much, Rajesh.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Thank you very much.
Thanks you very much.
Thank you.
comes on the line of Florian Cesnedes from OdoBHS.
Please go ahead.
Good afternoon.
Thank you very much for taking my follow-up question.
A question on the cardio business.
Assuming positive results on Pelacarsen later this year